kount.net 2019-04-25

# Privacy Policy | Kount

Effective Date: January 4, 2019

Kount Inc. (Kount) is committed to maintaining the privacy of personal information that you provide to us when using any of our online services. This privacy policy describes how we treat the information we receive when you transmit data to any machine owned by Kount.

## Web Form Information 

When you submit information to Kount, we may collect personally identifiable information from you that may include your name, address, and email address. We do not knowingly collect personal information from persons under the age of 18. 

## Web Site Usage Information 

We automatically collect IP addresses and web site usage information from you when you access any of our online services. This information helps us evaluate how our visitors and subscribers use and navigate our web sites on an aggregate basis, including but not limited to the number and frequency of visitors and subscribers to each web page, and the length of their visits.

###  How We Use Information Collected 

We may use information in the following ways:

  * For the purposes you specifically provided the information including, for example, enabling us to respond to your questions about our products and services. 
  * To register you as a client and establish an account for you. 
  * To send you email notifications about our new or existing Kount products and services, special offers, or to otherwise contact you. 
  * To enhance existing features or develop new features, products, and services. 
  * To provide advertisers and other third parties with aggregate information about our user base and usage patterns. 
  * To allow us to personalize the content and advertising that you and others see based on personal characteristics or preferences. 
  * To detect and prevent fraudulent transactions. 

Except as specifically set forth in this privacy policy, we will not share your personally identifiable information outside of Kount. Note that we do not use, rent, or sell any personal data for purposes materially different from those for which it was originally provided. If this practice should change in the future, we will provide individuals with prior notice and instruct them as to how they can exercise opt-out or opt-in choice, as applicable. We may disclose and use personally identifiable information in special circumstances where it is necessary to enforce our service agreements or terms of use (for example to protect our intellectual property rights). We may also disclose or use your personal information when we, in good faith, believe that the law may require us to do so. Please be aware that Kount may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

### Service Providers, Business Partners and Others 

Kount may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our service, to provide the service on our behalf, to perform Site-related services (including but not limited to maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of our web sites’ features) or to assist us in analyzing how our web sites and services are used. These third parties have access to your personal Information only for purposes of performing these tasks on our behalf.

### Business Transfers 

Kount may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your personal information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy.

### Cookies 

We define a cookie as any string of data that is automatically stored on your computer upon access to our online services. Kount employs cookies to assign temporary identification numbers to machines that access our web servers. This information enables us to deliver faster service to our subscribers, prevent denial of service attacks on our systems, and detect and prevent fraudulent transactions. All Kount cookies are:

  * Of limited duration 
  * Less than 5KB in length 
  * Only visible to Kount web servers 
  * Devoid of any personally identifiable information 

### Security 

The personally identifiable information we collect about you is stored in limited access servers. We maintain safeguards to protect the security of these servers and your personally identifiable information. We retain personally identifiable information only as long as necessary to complete a purchase, thwart fraud, provide customer service, or maintain your account with us.

### EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Frameworks 

Kount complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Kount has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>. 

Kount is a "processor" of personal data as defined in Article 2(e) of the Directive. Kount provides processing services in the US for its European Union and Swiss business partners (“EU and Swiss Business Partners”) which include merchants and financial institutions and other applicable businesses. Kount also provides processing for US based business partners. We act as a data processor and data importer on behalf of our EU and Swiss Business Partners, and accordingly we follow the instructions provided by each Business Partner with regard to the collection, processing and protection of personal data provided to us by each such Business Partner. Each Business Partner acts as the data controller and data exporter for any personal data within its control. EU and Swiss individuals should contact the applicable Business Partner with questions regarding the collection of their personal data. 

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles (“the Principles”), Kount commits to resolve questions and complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy and/or the types of data Kount collects, should contact Kount at [privacy@kount.com](mailto:privacy@kount.com). Please note that Kount acts as a data processor and the majority of the data Kount processes is anonymous. In instances of onward transfers, Kount has the responsibility for processing personal information that is not anonymized in accordance with the Principles and subsequent transfers to third parties that may act on Kount’s behalf. Kount will remain liable under the Principles if its third-party agents process such non-anonymized personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles unless we can prove we were not a party to the events giving rise to the damages. Kount acknowledges the right of EU and Swiss individuals to access their personal data pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks. Any personal information that Kount collects that is not anonymous is available for European Union individuals to access upon request for correction or deletion. 

Written correspondence may be sent to:   
EU Privacy Mailbox   
917 S. Lusk Suite 301 Boise ID 83706

Kount has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/ for more information and to file a complaint. As a last resort, and in limited situations, European Union and Swiss individuals may seek redress from the Privacy Shield Panel, a binding arbitration mechanism. Kount is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). 

This policy was last updated 04 January 2019.
